We continue right along in our study of Romans this morning.
especially Romans chapter 12 with the theme of the
impact of the gospel.
Verse 6 to 8 speaks regarding its impact within
our personal ministries.
And since it's been, you know, a couple weeks.
Let's look at this part again so we can kind of, you know, get our mind right.
Romans 12, verse 6 through 8 says, having then gifts
differing according to the grace that is given
to us, whether prophecy, let us prophecy, according to
the proportion of faith, or ministry that is serving,
let us wait on our ministering, or the he
that teacheth on teaching, or he that exhorteth,
that's encouraging on exhortation.
He that giveth, let him do it with simplicity.
He that ruleth, that's to lead with diligence, and he
that showeth mercy with cheerfulness.
You and I have a responsibility to serve the king and
to do so together.
I need you to understand that God's design for
his people is to be a people.
Not a person, not a, not a,
just kind of isolated over here, and I, no, no, no, God designed.
He gave us the church.
We are called the bride of Christ.
He shed his blood so that we could be quickened
together with him in heavenly places.
In other words, what I'm trying to tell you is this is a team effort.
We are a family in Christ and each person has
a part and a role to play.
And that brings us to the next part of this study,
the impact of the gospel.
We already looked at in our personal ministry,
but also we're going to look at now the impact of the gospel in
our relationships.
We went over one verse 2 weeks ago.
says this in verse 9, let love be without the simulation.
Abhor that which is evil, cleave to that, which is good.
What that means is very simply, let love be
without hypocrisy, distance yourself from what is evil
and draw close to that, which is good.
Can I tell you something?
This has been on the forefront of my mind since I preached it.
You would be shocked if you really had this in
your heart and in your mind as you live your daily life.
Most of the love that we show, unfortunately,
can be hypocritical.
We love them to their face.
They talk about them behind their back.
Guys, listen, in this phone world, in the flesh that we
battle every single day, it's one of the easiest things to do is let our mouth run.
You do realize that a lot of people, that's what they think the church is, just
a bunch of gossiping slanderers.
Bunch of a bunch of self-righteous people that like to gather once
a week and act like they got it all together and live like the world the rest of the time.
Church, may that not be us here?
If we're going to love each other, which we're commanded to do, may it be without hypocrisy.
But I can tell you this, our community, the church, our families, our personal
lives, would all be better if we just apply this command to our lives.
And yes, it is a command.
I want to let you in on 2 secrets before we get going this morning.
First off, the 1st secret.
I don't know if you know it or not.
But living for Jesus is simple.
Y'all hear what I said?
Living for Jesus is simple.
Now notice the words that I use.
When I type words out to preach.
When I write them out to, I specifically pick each word.
Amen?
In other words, I did not say easy.
I said simple.
See, being Christ centered and all that we do is not always easy,
but it is simple.
See, God does not attempt to confuse us in our walk with him.
The spirit makes things as clear as they can be.
So many people come up and they
say, well, preacher, what about this?
And what about that?
And should we do this?
And should we do that?
And should I partake in this and should I partake in that?
And listen, if you're having to ask, that
means there's obviously something happening in your spirit.
The Holy Spirit is a lot smarter than I am.
Just follow him.
Now I can give you advice, but what we do is this.
We like to go to advice that agrees with what we want to do.
You know what I'm saying?
what I'm saying?
So you come to me or you go to somebody else and say, hey, listen, I've got this situation.
What should I do?
You get advice.
It's biblically sound.
It's doctrinally sound.
They show you the scripture says, hey, listen, this is how we ought to obey.
This is how you ought to walk and navigate this situation.
Well, you don't like that.
So what do you do?
You go to somebody else until you find someone to tell you what you want to hear.
Listen, that's not what we're called to do.
The Holy Spirit, we got to stop acting like the Holy
Spirit doesn't tell us and direct us and guide us and remind us
of things that we've been taught.
God did not cause to walk around, confuse wandering this earth.
We have a purpose and a mission and a vision of heaven.
Amen.
Are y'all women this morning?
Listen, living for Jesus, it's temple.
Just follow him.
If he says do it, do it.
If he says doesn't do it, don't do it.
Y'all with me?
Y'all not with me.
Okay.
But there's an inverse truth to that.
Living for Jesus is simple.
We may complicate it, but I can tell you what's complicated no matter what.
Living for the flesh, that's complicated.
You say, what are you talking about?
Well, if you want to live life on the perpetual edge of destruction and trouble.
Allow the flesh to lead.
There was a VBF song that has stuck in my mind for years, and the
main part of the song says this.
Sin messed everything up.
Was anyone here and we had that music in VBS, man, it was awesome.
It was like, it was like, sin, messed everything up, everything up.
then it was like, oh no, you know what I'm saying?
Like it was, and, you know, it wasn't how it was supposed to be, you know, originally
in the Garden of Eden.
You know what I'm saying?
Like it was cool, Taylor.
would have loved it.
But anyway, listen, it was a great song, man.
It was like a little rap.
And it's made for kids, right?
But the truth is for us as well.
Listen, sin does mess everything up.
Your sin will mess up your life if not handled with confession and repentance.
You want a life full of contentment, empty of daily shame
and complete with victory.
You live for Jesus.
If you want everything else that's not that, you live for the flesh.
Now, what does this have to do with Romans chapter 12?
understand everything.
Living for Jesus goes much further than
a daily devo, saying grace at each meal and church
once a week, living for Jesus, it literally pierces
every part of our life.
That's not just in our ministry, but that's also as we see
here in our relationships with one another, another.
The fact that we boil down, walking with Christ to
these things, the daily devo, you know, the same
grace of a meal, the church once a week.
The fact that we think that following Jesus is just checking these
things off a list, that is what has created a cultural
Christianity that is plaguing our homes and communities.
People now think that it is easy to
follow and love Jesus.
Let me just tell you something.
It's not.
There's going to be times to where it's difficult.
There's going to be times to where you got to make some hard decisions.
The decision and the right choice is simple,
but it's difficult to make that choice.
You got to stand up for the word.
You got to stand up for truth.
Now, we're going to go slow in this study because there's too much that we need to understand.
And so this morning we're going to read the next few verses here.
In verses 10 through 13, it says this.
If we're going to if we're going to have a proper relationship
with each other, right, if we're going to have the impact
of the gospel and it be evident in how we interact, then
we need to understand this.
It says this in verse 10, be kindly affection, one to another with brotherly
love, in honor of preferring one another.
Not slothful in business, fervent in spirit, serving the Lord,
rejoicing in hope, patient, and tribulation, continuing instant
in prayer, distributing to the necessity of saints, given to hospitality.
Again, we're looking at the title, the impact of the gospel
in relationships.
Let's pray.
Father, I thank you for your word.
And I just thank you for just a, just a wonderful,
sweet time of worship that we've had here today.
God, I pray, Lord, that again you use this vessel for an honorable use.
allow me to speak, God, as you would have me speak, God.
When I pray those that have ears to hear, may they hear?
In Jesus name, pray.
Amen.
Now, the way we're going to break this down is we're going to take one key
word from each of these commands, and we're going to expose the
importance of each in our lives.
So let's go ahead and get started.
In our relationships, because we've been saved and changed
by the gospel, because we are now new creations in
Christ, because the oldest passed away, and behold all is
new, because we no longer live for ourselves, but rather for Jesus, someone say amen.
If you're born again, that's you.
Everything I just said explains you and I.
Then we must be devoted.
We must be devoted.
Look again at verse 10.
Be kindly affectionate one to another with brotherly love
in honor preferring one another.
That phrase, kindly affection means literally
in the Greek, being very affectionate, loving
dearly, but also look at it, devoted.
It means to be devoted.
So it could read, be devoted, one to
another with brotherly love.
Now, there are those who think devotion to the things of God means simply
showing up or making a difficult decision, no matter the
hurt it may cause, and listen, I'm going to be honest with you.
I don't want to beat a dead horse here, but I led that way for probably 2 or 3 years.
It was my way of the highway.
And I had truth to stand upon.
If you didn't like it, I can't tell you how many times I pointed at
that door said, there's the door.
You can head on out.
Nobody cares.
Let me just tell you something.
That is selective scripture.
Are you with me?
For so long, my devotion to God's
word was at times selected.
Now, before you look at me all sideways, let me explain that.
I had no problem beating people over the head with truth.
I loved it.
Man, I love getting up here, stomping my feet.
Man, I used to even wear cowboy boots.
Does anyone remember when I used to wear cowboy boots preaching?
Was anyone here?
Look at that.
See, people actually remember that.
If I look close enough, there's a spot here on the stage,
I can't find it, but where my heel went through the stage because I was stomping so much.
How ridiculous is that?
But either way, that's what happened.
But listen, you got to understand.
I had no problem with that.
But I had a big problem with affection.
I had a big problem in loving dearly.
If you don't care when you hurt someone's feeling, there's a lack of devotion present in your life.
Now, listen, if you know me, you know I love to rag.
I love I love to roast.
I love to joke around and we're not we're not talking about the commaderie with the guys.
What I'm talking about is when you truly hurt somebody and
it does not bother you, there's something wrong.
Again, there's a balance.
Doctrine matters.
Church sanctity matters how we handle the sin of each other matters.
We cannot simply overlook it or brush it under the rug like we do so often.
To stand upon God's word does mean that hard decisions have to be made.
However, we must look at the complete word of God.
So right here to make a point.
Devotion speaks of how we interact with each other.
For example, we can confront someone's sin all day long, but
are we doing it biblically?
What does that look like?
What does it mean to confront someone's sin?
Well, look at Colossians 4.6?
Let your speech always be with grace.
As though seasoned with salt.
so that you will know how you should respond to each person.
Galatians 61.
Brethren, if any man is caught up in any trespass, that is sin,
you are you who are spiritual, restore such a one in a spirit of gentleness.
Each one looking to yourself so that you too will not be tempted.
See, God never permits us to be rude or high-minded when it
comes to each other, but rather meek and full of grace.
Even we have the power to control.
Even we have the power to destroy, even we have the power to let
someone know about their sin and the spread out, hey, this person's doing this.
Listen, hey, we got to understand, we got to have power controlled just like Christ did.
Here's another truth that we need to hear while focusing on both.
We got we got to focus on the sin.
But we must look deeper at the center than we do sin.
Are y'all women this morning?
Look, think with me now.
Does this make you uncomfortable?
And the reason that it makes us uncomfortable because as
I'm as I'm putting this together, I'm thinking, man, this is, you know, am I living this?
Am I walking in this?
Because listen, if I'm preaching and not walking, it's a problem.
Now, I'm not saying I'm perfect, okay?
And it does put me in some spots sometimes because y'all
have quoted me to my face.
And I don't like it.
But I do accept it.
I receive it.
What I'm trying to say is this.
listen.
Could it be that we get uncomfortable, looking
at the sinner deeper than the sin, because
we know that the only differences that our sin's private, now there's this public?
Let's think about that for a second.
If you were followed around in everything you did,
was shown publicly.
How would you like that?
Now, don't think that I'm saying, that sin is not a big deal.
a huge deal.
It's such a huge deal.
We can't mess up when we confront it.
We got to confront it correctly.
See, God's word gives us clear direction and went off and
is a forgotten part of our church and that's church discipline.
We love quote Matthew 18, right after some of the gossips.
Look at Matthew 18 verses 15 through 17.
Moreover, if your brother sins against you, go and tell him his fault
between you and him alone.
If he hears you, you have gained your brother.
But if you will not hear you, take with you one or 2 more that by
the mouth of 2 or 3 witnesses, every word may be established.
And if he refuses to hear them, tell it to the church.
But if he refuses even to hear the church, let him be to
you like a heathen, and a tax collector, your Bible probably
says an infidel.
Basically an unbeliever.
Now, we look at this, and every time someone comes to us
with with someone else's sin, we rightfully say,
hey, Matthew 18, have you gone to them?
But if we went to them, would we go to them with
the right heart posture?
Notice, why not just kick them out immediately?
Why not just see someone and sin
against you and say, you know what, I'm done with them.
I'm through with them, get them out of my face.
Why not shun them like other religions do?
Why not just shame them or isolate them until
they decide to leave anyway?
Then we just say, good riddance.
Listen, these are usually the strategies the church takes when
something happens between people.
We do all that we can without just straight up telling them, I
want you to leave, but we do everything we can to make them leave.
Because here's the thing.
That is looking at the sin more than the person.
That is perceived power out of control.
That is a complete lack of grace in view.
The goal in any conflict, a brother or sister in the
church can be involved in is complete reconciliation.
Again, look at verse 15.
The 1st step.
Moreover, if your brother sins against you, go and tell him his fault between you and him alone.
If he hears you.
Look what it says.
You have gained a brother.
Is that not beautiful?
I've heard people say, well, I just there's just no way I can be in the same room
with them for any amount of time.
So it's just best that I leave, so I don't cause any trouble.
You can leave, but your heart's wrong.
And so guess what?
You're going to bring that heart posture wherever else you go.
And guess what's going to happen because that heart posture hasn't changed?
Someone else is going to offend you.
You're gonna do the same thing.
That's how people just church hop, church hop,
group hop, this hop, that hop.
We just like to walk around, just where we want to go because we just stay hurt.
It's a heart posture.
This takes devotion.
It takes that that kindly affection, love.
to reconcile.
By the way, it's what keeps the family together.
Look again at Romans 1210, be kindly affection.
to one another, brotherly love and honor preferring one another.
Do you know what the gospel does?
The gospel brings you into a new family.
I think we've forgotten that in modern church.
Why?
Because we're so digital.
We're so screen oriented.
We don't have to be at church because we can miss.
We just watch it.
Now, listen, hey, the minister that we have with our live stream and our AV
team, man, it is, it is getting the gospel out there.
We're going to not do anything but make it better and better as we go.
That's not what I'm saying.
But what I'm saying is the culture that we live in, we can do or
not with it, whether we have each other or not, it doesn't matter us.
We, we, we, we will doom scroll on Facebook.
We'll put this fake stuff in our face and think that everything's
fine and that's how we get our field.
Can I tell you something?
If the enemy has done anything so well,
What he's done is he's replaced family with social media.
Because we can get our fill on a screen now.
And so when we get with actual people, now we don't know how to handle it.
So I'll just back up and I don't want to be confrontational.
No, no, no, no.
How about we have a devotion to each other and work it out.
Are y'all women this morning?
The tone of this command is obviously pointing and assuming a family
bond within the believers.
It says, be kindly affection, one to another, with brotherly love.
As a matter of fact, the Greek term used for brotherly here means
it means love for fellow believer, formally
brotherly kindness.
Do you know what is the greatest indication that a church loves Jesus?
How they love each other.
Is there is there love active?
Is there love evident?
easily seeing how they interact and serve with and for each other.
Is there love spread to those who are new to the family,
just like those who are old to the family, or vice versa?
Church, if we don't have love, what do we have?
First Corinthians 13 has something to say about that.
We're just making a bunch of noise.
Just some clanging symbols.
Have you ever heard symbols out of place?
It's not, I should have brought some this morning.
It's not good.
They have their proper place, but when they're at a place, it's terrible.
See, without love, this is a business rather than a ministry.
Without love, this is a burden rather than a blessing.
Without love, there will be no forgiveness, no reconciliation, no
restoration, no discipleship.
That's why the 1st part of our mission statement here is Cedar Grove
is love others unconditionally.
to prove our devotion and affection for your family, for your fellow church family.
ask yourself this question.
to gauge and measure where you are in your devotion
to each other.
Ask this question to yourself and answer honestly, how easy
is it for you to write somebody off?
How easy.
I have this thing and this problem and and the
people closest to me have told me this for many, many years.
I trust so quickly.
I'm talking about if you promise me the world, let's go get the world, baby.
If you tell me you going to do something, I just assume that's going to get done.
Are y'all, I mean, call me faulty or not.
don't know.
When someone comes in, and man, they got all, they got all the stuff and they
can do it and they can, and they're excited and they're passionate, and they're
like, hey, let's let's go take the world for Christ, you know what I'm doing?
I'm packing my bag.
Let's go, let's get it done.
Let's make this happen.
But what has happened over the past years or years,
rather, is this, is that, man, my trust has been broken.
Time after time, after time.
I get this promise, hey, let's go do this and all of a sudden they're gone.
And then I sit here, I look like a fool because I'm like, whoa, I invested.
And I, what's happened?
And it happens over and over and over again.
And every single time, just about, is what I get told.
Well, you know, we told you that was coming.
And you know what I do?
I sit there and say, you know what, you're right.
Stink and forget everybody.
I'm done with it all.
And then the next person comes in and promise me the world, man, let's go do it.
Come on.
I can't help it.
It's just part of my
just part of how God created me.
I want to serve with you.
I want to live this life with you.
Now, listen, let me get on my little soapbox for a second.
I ain't got no friends outside of y'all.
So measure your friendship with me.
If it's lacking, that means it's just lacking.
There's nothing else, you know what I'm saying?
You are my life.
I'm blessed to be able to be your pastor, and the way that works for
me is my life is revolved around Christ, therefore,
it's revolved around you.
Now, you maybe sit there and think, well, you don't ever call me.
Well, you don't ever call me, dog.
Sorry.
My bad.
I snuck out.
But how easy is it for you to write someone off.
That's the question that we're asking.
And I said what I said because this.
And I have faults.
And don't get me wrong, like I, there's, there's things in my leadership that are not
good, but there's people that could walk through that door right now.
And I'm telling you right now, we can get right back to where we were.
Doesn't mean I don't know.
Doesn't mean I don't see.
Doesn't mean I don't I don't have the more caution.
But I, there's something about that if someone wants
to serve Jesus with me, then I want to serve Jesus with them.
Guys, listen, how easy it is to write someone off?
Some of us, man, we can we get hurt one time.
We get burnt one time by somebody.
Man, they don't mess.
We can see them on the side of the road.
Well speed up.
We see him coming in a church.
You know what we do?
What are they doing back?
Well, you don't know what they've been through the last month or so.
You don't know if God is humbled them.
You don't know if their flesh has been destroyed.
You don't know if their family is in shambles.
They might be coming in here broken and listen, hey, you know what's the most amazing thing?
There's people that have left this church, but they still call me.
They say, Pastor, I need some help.
May I never say, you're not part of this.
Lose my number.
You got to be devoted.
Got to be devoted.
This will show the affection you have for one another.
Brothers and sisters, as long as we are loving Jesus like we should.
There ought to be nothing that we cannot work through together.
But there's also a mindset, and again,
I'm going to be talking some radical stuff here because I know what it sounds like.
But as a mindset that I believe, especially in a
modern church, it has, um, it has
hindered so many churches from having the impact that they could.
And this is the mindset.
Well, preacher, my real family comes 1st no matter what.
This is a smokescreen for neglecting the church.
Well, you know, my family, they, they, you know, every
Sunday morning, they have brunch and what do
you want me to do, not just not be in my family?
No, tell me you go to church.
Or not.
No, no, you just let them know where you stand.
Listen to me.
I love my family.
My family has a weekly Monday night dinner.
We cherish our time together.
what we have is very rare.
And we acknowledge that and we try to protect it and we love it.
We love eating together.
We all happen to be able to cook, and so we throw down.
Dining's just so good.
it's awesome.
Right?
And so but here's the thing.
I am close with my in-laws, I have been since high school.
If you ask me how my family is, I'll tell you, God has blessed me abundantly,
but there's something to understand.
My family cannot take me away from
my devotion to my church family.
Again, it sounds radical, but please understand, if I didn't have scripture to
back it up, I wouldn't have mentioned it.
You say, what do you mean?
Well, after being firmly rejected by the religious leaders, Jesus
paints a clear picture of truth here.
In Matthew 12, let me read you some scripture here.
It says this.
While he yet talked to the people, behold, his mother and his brethren stood without.
Desiring to speak with him.
Then one said unto him, behold thy mother and thy brethren, stand
without, desiring to speak with thee.
But he answered and said unto him and told him, who is my mother and who are my brethren?
And he stretched forth his hand toward his disciples
and said, behold, my mother and my brethren.
For whosoever shall do the will of the Father, of my Father, which is
in heaven, the same as my brother and sister and mother.
Now, allow me to clarify this because you're thinking, hold on,
what in the world is Jesus saying here?
Was Jesus perfect?
That took too long.
Amen.
Okay.
So there's no way that
in this situation he's dishonoring his mother.
Because that's the 5th commandment.
You hear me?
So he's not dishonoring his family.
He's not dishonoring his mother.
Right?
Jesus loved his earthly mother dearly.
Sometimes we forget that Jesus had a mama.
We forget that he had brothers and he had sisters.
He had an earthly father.
Like, he had chores in the house growing up.
Like, we forget that he was fully God and fully man
all together at the same time.
You say, explain it, I can't.
I just did.
Fully gone, fully man.
So what are we trying to say here?
He was perfect in all his ways.
So why did he go about the situation like he did?
I like how God questions, explains this because it is.
It's a very confounding situation.
Upon asking the question, who are my mother and
brothers, Jesus answers it.
Pointing out his disciples and telling the crowd
that his disciples were his mother and brothers.
In other words, his family.
While that initially may have puzzled his listeners,
he clarified immediately, for whoever does the will
of my father in heaven is my brother and sister and mother.
In other words, the relationships hear me.
In other words, the relationships that really matter in
the internal scheme of things are those relationships
based on rightly relating to God.
I'm not saying that you must reject your earthly family.
I'm saying to bring them in the fold.
so that we can have an impact for Christ together.
Where do your devotions lie?
Is your affection set to temporary or eternal things?
Listen, I know what you're thinking right now.
If you're someone who, man, you know, family comes
1st and that I'm not saying don't love your family,
but if you're someone that's like that and you're irritated now, like, well, that just
doesn't that doesn't apply to me, well, it applied to Jesus.
You may ask, how am I supposed to be devoted like this?
This is a big, this is kind of a big deal right here.
Like, you're talking about some serious love.
I mean, you're talking about some serious adjustments in my life.
Okay?
Well, God's word answers that.
Look at in verse 10, be kindly affection, devoted, one to another
with brotherly love, in honor of preferring one another.
Let me ask you something.
Isn't it anyone competitive in here?
Raise your hand if you're competitive.
Hey, are you not competitive?
Not anymore.
Okay, I've worked out with Taylor.
He a little competitive.
Listen, I'm kind of sort of competitive.
I've gotten better.
No, stop it.
Y'all living in the past.
For real living in the in the past.
Stop it.
Wesley knows, I have gotten better in my competitiveness.
Okay, thank you.
He's been there for all of it.
You know what I'm saying?
So I like to win.
Okay?
I like this is what I say to people when I used to coach.
Um, that wasn't a that wasn't a good tenure, so I had to quit.
But, um, we did get a chip though.
But anyway, I said, lady, if you like to lose, that
there's a word in the dictionary for you, and that's a loser, you know?
But listen, we're all competitive in some ways.
Right?
We want to do good.
We want to do, you know, right, and sometimes even do better than someone else.
This takes competitiveness and brings it to a biblical application for our life.
Look at the scripture again, in honor of preferring one another.
This phrase, if you look at the language, gives the
idea of outdoing one another in showing honor.
So the mindset here is you are not going to outdo me in the way I love you.
That's right, Taylor.
Yeah.
I'm gonna love you more than you love me.
But listen, hey, think about that for a 2nd now.
If we all did that, what kind of impact would that make?
Now, what does it mean to honor one another, okay?
Now hear me because you're thinking, man, this is, you know, this
is we're breaking this down here.
What does it mean to honor?
because that's important in honor preferring one another.
We understand what that phrase means, outdoing one another and showing honor,
but what is even honoring?
Well, it means to respect.
To give status to?
Listen to this.
I like this, to attribute value or worth.
In other words, when you come around the church family,
Your worth goes up.
Not that you were worthless before.
But you lift it up.
By your family.
You're honored.
Church, do you get it?
Scripture repeats this theme all throughout.
Jesus set the standard in Matthew 20, verse 16.
So the last shall be 1st and the 1st last.
Paul writes about it in Philippians chapter 2, verse 3.
Do nothing from selfishness or empty conceit, but with humility
of mind, regard one another as more important than yourself.
Could you imagine the influence our church would have if we regarded
each other in such honor?
Not seeing ourselves as most important, but seeing those
that were serving for Christ is more important.
This really should be the most evident characteristic of Cedar Grove.
First, that's only as chapter 4, verse 9.
Now as to the love of the brethren.
You have no need for anyone to write to you, for you yourselves
are taught by God, to love one another.
Let me just tell you something.
think about what Paul just said.
I don't even have to write this.
When you become born again,
The God who is loved puts his Holy
Spirit, who therefore is love in you, you don't have to be told to love.
Out of a saved and regenerate heart, it just comes out.
So if it doesn't, what's going on?
We see this pattern for a successful marriage, right?
Ephesians 5, verse 25 through 29.
Husbands love your wives just as Christ also loved the church and gave himself up for her.
so that he might sanctify her, having cleansed her by the washing of word,
of water with the word, that he might present to himself the church in
all her glory, having no spot or wrinkle or any such
thing, but that she would be holy and blameless.
So husbands ought also to love their own wives.
Listen as their own bodies.
Who loves his own wife, loves himself.
For no one ever hated his own flesh, but nourisheth it,
and cherishes it just as Christ also does the church.
You know why your marriage is in trouble because you're not devoted in affection?
You're not respecting the value of your spouse.
Husbands, do you bring value and worth to your life?
Would you bring it down?
Wives, do you bring value and worth to your husband?
Do you bring it down?
This goes for every one of our relationships within the body of Christ.
How can it be that we are able to fellowship and love those who are far from God
more successfully at times and more comfortably than the
ones within our own church family?
We'll go to the CMAs with our buddies and have a good old time, but we won't come
to a fellowship of the church because, man, I just can't stand that person.
Come on now.
We're talking eternity here.
I used to tell people all the time, listen, if you don't like me, if
you say that I'm saved, you better get the liking me.
I'm going to pray God puts my mansion right by yours.
I'm gonna mow my yard and blow all the leaves in your yard.
Say, love your brother?
No, I'm kidding.
That's hypocrisy and love, okay?
Don't do that.
But this is a sign that we have lost our time affection
one to another when it's more difficult to love each other here
than it is to love those out there.
Now we used to love others unconditioned no matter what.
But let me just tell you something.
The book of assurance, you can read 1st John, talks about the brethren, talks
about brothers and sisters, talks about the family, that's talking about us.
If we can't love each other, how in the world can we love anyone else?
And for those who may harbor hate for a brother or sister in Christ in your heart,
that is not something to allow a fester.
You say, I don't hate anybody.
Your actions say you do.
You know, if we had a correct assessment of our own cells, we wouldn't
have to, we wouldn't have to go so long stumbling over our own sin.
That's why we have self-examination.
Man, there's people that excuse hate for, well, I just don't get along with them.
Well, well, I I don't hate them.
I just don't want to ever talk to them or see them ever again in my life.
Well, I don't hate them, but man, if they sit, if they sit by
me or 2 rows by me, I'm getting up and I'm moving.
I don't hate them.
Man, if they're in line at the potluck.
I'm I'm mad.
Guys listen, that's hate.
That's the stain.
You say, well, I get to choose to hate who I want.
Okay, that's cool.
Yeah.
First John 211, but the one who hates his brother is in the darkness and walks in the darkness.
and does not know where he is going because the darkness has blinded his eyes.
You know what the dumbest thing to do?
Walk in the darkness when it's a light switch.
Amen.
You know how many times we've done that?
We're sitting there with...
We walk around spiritually in the darkness, when all we got
to do is love like we're supposed to, and the light gets turned on.
Are y'all with me this morning?
I mean, y'all stand at me like you hating on me, you know?
I don't know.
It is impossible to love God properly while hating a fellow saint.
We're going to talk next week more about church hurt and
stuff, but I want you to understand something.
Is our devotion to each other evident?
Through the hurt, through the ups and downs, through the disagreements, through
the conflict, through the tension, I can guarantee you this.
listen to me.
When it comes to Cedar Grove,
There might be 2 or 3 people that's here right now that's been
hurt more than I've been hurt here.
I'm not I'm not trying to sit here and be a big baby.
I'm just letting you know the truth.
I've been here long enough to be hurt quite a few times.
Okay?
What I'm trying to say is this.
We can't live in that hurt.
We can't live in that hate.
Our devotion for each other has to override that.
So is your devotion evident.
How easy is to write each other off?
Do we pursue reconciliation?
God has not called us to be the same, but rather gloriously different for his glory.
So when we butt heads because we're very different, that's actually
God's plan.
Not necessarily to butt heads, but to be different.
Could you imagine if we were all the same?
I wouldn't like most of y'all, if you just like me, you know what I'm saying?
Listen, this is not a weakness' strength.
So this morning, I want to ask you something before we go.
I'm going to ask those questions one more time.
Now think about it real quick.
Is your devotion to others evident?
If people looked at you, would they think you're loving or cold?
You know, if we took a survey, people say surveys don't work because people aren't honest.
If we took an honest survey,
And people ask, hey, that person right there, you think they love
the people that's around them, what would people say?
How easy is it for you just to forget somebody and say, I'm done with you.
You're out of my life forever.
I'm talking about the brethren.
I talking about the family of God here.
When's the last time you pursued reconciliation?
Guys, listen, this is what makes our love evident.
These things right here.
So it has bound eyes closed over this place.